It will cost you everything.
Blood Diamond is a drama, thriller, action film directed by Edward Zwick.
An ex-mercenary turned smuggler.
A Mende fisherman.
Amid the explosive civil war overtaking 1999 Sierra Leone, these men join for two desperate missions: recovering a rare pink diamond of immense value and
rescuing the fisherman's son, conscripted as a child soldier into the brutal rebel forces ripping a swath of torture and bloodshed countrywide.
Danny Archer, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Solomon Vandy, played by Djimon Hounsou.
Maddy Bowen, played by Jennifer Connelly.
Dia Vandy, played by Kagiso Kuypers.
Colonel Coetzee, played by Arnold Vosloo.
Cordell Brown, played by Antony Coleman.
Blood Diamond is a 2006 American political war thriller film directed and co-produced by Edward
Zwick and starring Leonardo DiCaprio, Jennifer Connelly, and Djimon Hounsou.
The title refers to blood diamonds, which are diamonds mined in war zones and sold to finance
conflicts, and thereby profit warlords and diamond companies around the world.
Set during the Sierra Leone Civil War of 1991–2002, the film depicts a country torn
apart by the struggle between government loyalists and insurgent forces.
It also portrays many of the atrocities of that war, including the rebels' amputation of
civilians' hands to discourage them from voting in upcoming elections.
The film's ending, in which a conference is held concerning blood diamonds, refers to a
historic meeting that took place in Kimberley, South Africa, in 2000.
It led to development of the Kimberley Process Certification Scheme, which sought to certify the origin of rough diamonds in order
to curb the trade in conflict diamonds; the certification scheme has since been mostly abandoned as ineffective.
The film received positive reviews, with praise directed
toward the performances of DiCaprio and Hounsou.
The film grossed $171 million worldwide and received five Oscar nominations,
including Best Actor for DiCaprio and Best Supporting Actor for Hounsou.
DiCaprio received a nomination for a Golden Globe Award for Best Actor – Motion Picture
Drama (also nominated that year in the same category for The Departed).
In addition, DiCaprio and Hounsou were nominated for Outstanding Male Actor in a Leading Role and
Outstanding Male Actor in a Supporting Role at the 13th Screen Actors Guild Awards.
The film explores themes of bootlegger, journalist,
smuggling (contraband), loss of loved one, africa.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.